最后  我要说的是我们会严肃处理此事
In closing, I can tell you we take this very seriously.
无论是本地警方还是药品管理局
APD as well as the DEA.
阻止冰毒的生产和销售
Stopping the manufacture and sale of methamphetamines
仍是当务之急
Remains one of our highest priorities.
贵校失窃的实验室仪器
And the theft of lab equipment from your school
也将是我们的工作重心
Is also receiving our highest attention.
请放心  我们会不遗余力地
Rest assured, no stone will go unturned
寻找这些事情的相关负责人员
In our search for the person or persons responsible for this.
如果你们还有什么疑问  现在就提出来
If you have any questions, now would be the time.
你说话的口气好像你们还没有抓到人
You're talking like you haven't caught anybody yet.
那个在学校里交易毒品的看门人呢
What about the janitor that was dealing drugs at the school?
没有任何迹象表明此人在出售毒品
There is no indication that this individual was selling drugs.
他被捕的原因是
He was arrested for having
在其车中找到少量大麻
a small amount of marijuana in his car.
并不是在学校里
Not in the school.
而且他因此被开除了
And he's since been fired.
我听说他有前科
I heard he had a record.
我想知道当初他是怎么会被聘用
I'd like to know how he got a job here in the first place.
没错  为什么没有调查背景
Exactly. Why wasn't there a background check?
有过
There was one.
我们正在复查聘用政策
We're currently reviewing our hiring policies.
你们还要做得更好
You better be doing more than that.
那人是在我女儿面前被逮捕的
He was arrested in front of my daughter.
那个人在偷实验室仪器  对吗
This guy was stealing the lab equipment, right?
现在  我们并不这么认为
That's not our thinking at this time.
而是在寻找同样能有接触途径的人
We are looking at others who also had access,
但不局限于维修职工
But not limited to the maintenance staff.
你是说有人非法闯入吗
Are you saying there was a break-in?
我们知道具体发生时间吗
Do we know exactly when this happened?
我想知道  是不是在上课时间
I mean, could it have been during school hours?
我们无法确定具体日期和时间
We haven't been able to establish a date or time,
不过没有任何闯入的迹象
But there is no sign of breaking or entering.
那么  那个人有钥匙
So...whoever took it had a key?
我们说的是监守自盗
We're talking inside job?
是学校内部人员吗
Someone who's still at the school?
目前  我无法跟你讨论细节问题
At this time I'm not able to discuss the details with you,
但是我可以告诉你的是
But we can tell you is that
我们有一批优秀的探员
We have some very good people
在调查这个案子
working very hard on this case.
对不起  长官  你的回答太含糊其词
I'm sorry, officer. But that sounds like double-talk.
我们在试图保护我们的孩子
We're trying to protect our children.
你们要和我们在同一条战线
You have to level with us.
实际上  我们提供了手头所有的信息
Really, we are giving you all the information we have.
你知道我喜欢怎样的学校吗
You know what I'd like to see in this school?
没有毒品
Drug never does.
没错  不能有缉毒犬  金属探测器
Yeah, dogs, and metal detectors,
还有不能搜查储物柜和连环漫画
And locker searches, and strip searches.
我们区有严格的政策
Our district has strict policies...
我在加拿大时听说一家学校
I heard about this school in Canada.
逮捕了一位携带毒品的场地管理员
They arrested one of their groundskeepers with drugs.
第二天发现
And the next day they found out over
超过半数的学生服过大量迷幻药
Half of the students were high on LSD.
迷幻药  你打算什么时候告诉我们迷幻药的事情
LSD? When were you gonna tell us about the LSD?
没有  没人说迷幻药
No. please. No one said anything about LSD.
被偷的仪器怎么样
What about the equipment that was stolen?
仪器是从我们的化学实验室被偷
The equipment was taken from our chemistry department.
我希望有人能说下详细情况
And I would like someone to give us some specifics.
沃尔特
Walt?
我在
Yeah.
怀特先生正在休病假
Mr. White is currently on medical leave.
但是他负责科学部的事务
But as he's chair of the science department,
他作出了很多特殊贡献
He's made a very special effort to be with us here.
首先我要感谢他
And I'd like to take a moment to thank him for that.
您能不能跟我们说下
Could you please tell us more
被偷的实验仪器情况吗
About the equipment that was taken?
-有请  -好的
- Please. - Yes.
谢谢大家
And thank you.
失窃的实验仪器详细清单如下
The inventory list for the missing lab wares are as follows:
一个5升的圆底烧瓶
One 5,000 milliliter round bottom boiling flask,
一个800毫升的凯氏冷却瓶
One kjeldahl-style recovery flask, 800 milliliters,
两个蒙面防毒面具
Two full-face respirators,
一些分离漏斗
Some sep funnels,
一个带温度计固定夹的底座
A sill head with a thermometer holder...
我的膝盖
Ow, my knee.
哪里来的感觉
Where... did that come from?
为什么TMD这么爽
And why was it so damn good?
因为这是非法行为
Because it was illegal.
绝
命
毒
师
第一季
第七集
本字幕由YYeTs人人影视翻译制作
更多美剧字幕 请登陆 www.YYeTs.net
■
翻译：joanna    老奶奶    小松狮    夜    缭乱
时间轴：永恒の幻想     特效：Will
■
校对：冰卡      后期：冰河       监制：蛐蛐
地下室
The basement.
当然还没有修好
Unfinished, of course.
但是看下这些空间
But just look at all this space.
你可以把这里想成是娱乐室  媒体室
You gotta think rec room, media room.
想象一下你能在这里做的所有事情
Just imagine all the things you could do down here.
请记住  你们是因为优美的环境才买这个房子
Now remember, you're buying for this fantastic neigorhood.
大片草坪  大树成荫
Big lawns and shade tress.
离乡村俱乐部只有步行的距离
Walking distance to the country club.
这里是怎么回事
What happened there?
小修了一下  不过这幢房子框架很好
Bit of a fixer, but this house has great bones.
看完这个  我还有很多
You know what? We're zeroing in. I've got another listing,
在那边的角落还有全新的
Brand-new, right around the corner.
你好
Hi.
需要提前预约的
It's by appointment only.
我来看房东的
I'm here to see the owner.
他在
He's in the...
休养车里
Recreational vehicle.
请提前预约
Yo, it's appointment only!
你感觉如何
How you feeling?
和你看到的一样好
About as good as you look.
天哪  你看上去像莱克斯·卢瑟[超人的女友]
Jeez, you look like... Lex Luthor.
我到医院看望过你  不过你在昏迷
Listen, I visited you in the hospital, but you were asleep.
没错  瘦子彼得说你想要屠库的地址
Yeah, Skinny Pete said you wanted Tuco's address.
好像要去报复人家
Acting like you were all out for blood.
你还活着  很明显你没去是明智的
You are alive, so obviously you wised up.
-不  我真的去见他了  -胡说
- No, I did go see him. - Bullshit.
你要卖房子了吗
Are you selling your house?
我把两个人变成了肉泥
I got two dudes that turned into raspberry slushie
放厕所里冲走
And flushed down my toilet.
我都没法打扫卫生
I can't even take a proper dump in there.
整幢该死的房子现在一定在闹鬼
The whole damn house has got to be haunted by now.
你不会真的去见屠库吧
You didn't actually go see Tuco?
给你
Here.
一共有17500
That is seventeen-five.
正好是35000的一半
Your half of the 35,000.
另外还有15000  也都归你了
Plus there's an extra 15 in there. It's all yours.
是你赚来了
You've earned it.
你从屠库那里拿的
You got this money from Tuco.
你想说的就是屠库给你钱
So Tuco gave you this is what you're saying.
-我们做了个交易  -你们做交易
- We made a deal. - You made a deal?
-没错  -等等
- That's right. - Wait.
你为什么要和那个小人做交易
Why would you make a deal with that scumbag?
你看到他是怎么对我的吗
You see what he did to me?
因为我觉得我们可以合伙做生意
Because I think that we can do business together.
我们达成了共识
We came to an understanding.
没门  知道吗  你们之间没有共识
No way, man! Okay? No understanding.
看看你手上的钱
Take a look at the money in your hand.
想想每周都能赚这么多
Now just imagine making that every week.
没错
That's right.
每周2磅  每磅卖35000
Two pounds a week. 35,000 a pound.
你都没跟我打声招呼  你告诉
Without even talking to me, you told...
这个有病的傻瓜
This insane ass clown
瞎眼的杀手
Dead-eyed killer that, uh...
我们每周给他2磅
That we would give him two pounds a week?
我们是指适当扩大我们的运营
We'll just scale up our operation.
我们可以增加几小时
We'll add a few more hours...
别跟我说时间
Don't talk to me about hours.
如果他在骗你呢  我们怎么拿到钱
What about pseudo, man? How are we gonna get that?
你以为冰毒小精灵会拿给我们吗
You think the meth fairy is just gonna bring it to us?
我花了一周时间去弄这些原料
It takes me a week to get this stuff.
我在拉斯·克鲁塞斯奔来跑去
I'm driving all the way out to Las Cruces.
来回200英里去跟马甲接头
200 miles each way to meet up with my smurfs...
-马甲  -去杂货店的那家伙
- Smurfs?  - The dudes who go to the drugstores,
一次拿上几盒再卖给我
And get a couple boxes at a time and sell them to me.
那估计就只有
And that's maybe only good for,
大概半磅重
Like, maybe a half pound worth.
看见了么  这就是你绝妙商业计划中的瓶颈
See, that's the bottleneck in your brilliant business plan.
好了
All right.
当然  你要是事先问我
Of course you would have known that
你早就知道了
If you would have just asked me.
嗯  我们又见面了
Well, here we are again.
是啊又见面了
Here we are.
-斯凯勒  你气色不错  -谢谢
- Skyler, you look great. - Thank you.
你这应该差不多有六  七个月了吧
You must be, what, six, seven months?
感觉怎样
How goes it?
还不错
It's great...
就是每五分钟就要蹒跚着去厕所
Other than waddling to the bathroom every five minutes.
下周要开宝宝派对  所以
The baby shower's next week. It'll be good to...
最好能让斯凯勒享受一次
It'll be good to have a day that's...
属于她自己的一天
Just about Skyler.
挺体贴
Very nice.
谢谢
Thank you.
沃尔特  我看你好像适应了掉发
Well, Walt, I see you've committed to the hair loss.
是啊
Yeah.
-你感觉怎样呢  -还行
- How do you feel? - Oh, okay.
其实很有形象
You know, pretty decent actually.
他气色好多了  你看
His color is better. You know, his energy.
他体力方面也
And he's even more...
好多了
Physical.
体力方面
More physical?
呃  性方面
Well... sexual.
活分一些
Frisky, actually.
我是说  这是个好兆头吧  对吗
I mean, that's got to be a good sign, right?
当然  我也这么认为
Sure, I'll take that.
对吗  沃尔特
Right, Walt?
那是不是意味着化疗起作用了
Couldn't that mean that the Chemo is working?
可能只表明
It may just mean that we've got
止吐药的药效到了
The anti-emetics tuned right.
说实话  要等到沃尔特完成这一阶段的化疗
Truth is, until Walt's finished this round of Chemo.
再做个正子扫描  现在还不能下定论
And we look at a new PET scan, we just can't say for sure.
我们还要不要做其它什么呢
Isn't there anything else we could be doing?
我一直再考虑关于
I've been wondering about...
辅助药物
Alternative medicine.
就是  中医一类的
I mean, Eastern Healing.
疗效全面一些
You know, holistic.
这个  我不好说它功效如何
Well, I can't speak to its efficacy.
但是只要它不影响我们的疗法
But as long as it doesn't interfere with our treatment,
一切能够带给病人希望
Anything that helps my patient have a better outlook,
带给他们健康的东西  我都欢迎
A better comfort, is fine by me.
那么你是指其实是心理作用
So you're saying it's all psychological.
不会有什么效果
It doesn't make any real difference.
只要有希望  结果也许大不相同
Having a better outlook can make a tremendous difference.
调整自我的期望值也很重要
But it's also important that we manage our expectations.
怎么
What?
垃圾场
A junkyard?
我来猜猜  是你选的地方
Let me guess, you picked this place?
这里怎么了  够私密
What's wrong with it? It's private.
这就像  良民想出来的交货地点
This is like... a non-criminal's idea of a drug meet.
就像  "哇  我在电影里见过  哇  看着我"
This is like, "Oh, I saw this in a movie. Oh, look at me."
那么你在哪儿做交易  教教我
So where do you transact your business? Enlighten me.
不晓得  塔克卡贝萨餐厅怎么样
I don't know. How about Taco Cabeza?
我有一半交易都是在那里完成的
Half the deals I've ever done went down at Taco Cabeza.
舒服  公开
Nice and public.
24小时营业
Open 24 hours.
从没有人在那儿被捉到过
Nobody ever gets shot at Taco Cabeza.
妈的  为什么不去商店街呢
Hell, why not the mall?
在过道等着  "喂  见面时间到了"
You know, wait at the gap. "Hey!  It's time for the meet."
我先放下无褶卡其裤
You know, I'll put down the flat-front khakis,
头转过去  拿一杯柳橙汁
Head on over, grab an orange julius.
跳过疯子屠库哪个部分
Skip the part where psycho lunatic Tuco
偷了我的药
You know, comes and steals my drugs
还把我打得血流不止
and leaves me bleeding to death.
听着  你不必呆在这里
Look, you don't have to be here for this.
知道吗  我认真的
Okay? I mean, seriously.
我没事
I'm okay.
切  我又不是懦夫
Nah, I'm no pussy.
我好得很
I'm good.
洁癖先生和他的伙计
Mr. Clean and his boy.
抱歉我要先跟你们磨合一下
I'm sorry that I had to tune you up.
相互尊重  你们要先付出才能得到
Respect, ese. You gotta give it to get it.
我们在这做什么
Hey, what are we doing way the hell out here?
怎么  他们把购物街关了
What, they close the mall or something?
海森堡  拜托  直截了当一点
Heisenberg, come on, break it out.
就这些  你就只有这么多
That's it? That's all you got?
我们制作方面出了点问题
We had some production problems.
0.53磅
Point five-three.
我觉得你玩了我们
I thought you was a player.
你告诉过我两磅的
You told me two pounds.
现在你用这些口香糖似的东西浪费我时间
And now you waste my time with these Chiclets?
一万七千五
Seventeen and a half..
减掉的五百是赔我耗的时间
Minus the half for wasting my time.
拜托
Hey, come on.
怎么你还想讨价还价
What, you're gonna argue?
你还有什么可说吗
You got something to say?
你们做事就像俩小婊子
You're doing business like a couple little bitches.
把钱给足了
I want all of it.
七万块
70 grand.
你说什么
What did you say?
你中意这批货  还想要更多
You like this product, and you want more.
当做投资吧
Consider it a capital investment.
草你妈的  你个秃子
Loco bald motherfucker.
五万二再加五百  二十五点的周利
Fifty-two and a half. 25 points vig.
周利
Vig?
利息  按周计算
Interest. Weekly.
行
Okay.
那应该是
That's...
本息一共65,625美元
$65,625 with interest.
-1.875磅  -不行
- 1.875 pounds. - No.
两磅  下周五拿
2 pounds. Next friday.
别给我出乱子
And no production problems.
你想不想要四磅
Can you handle 4 pounds?
听着  老头  说归说
Listen, old man. Talk is talk.
要是欠我钱的话
But owing me money...
后果很严重的
That's bad.
你刚刚干了什么
What did you just do?
四磅
4 pounds.
四磅  两磅还不够折腾啊
4 pounds, as if 2 pounds wasn't bad enough.
那相当于二三百盒的鼻窦炎药片
We're talking 200-300 boxes of sinus pills.
世界上可没那么多马甲
There ain't that many smurfs in the world.
我们这次不用假麻黄素
We're not going to need Pseudo-ephedrine.
我们要在管式炉里合成苯丙酮
We're going to make phenylacetone in a tube furnace,
再利用还原性氨化反应
Then we're gonna use Reductive Amination
来生成甲基苯丙胺[即冰毒]
to yield Methamphetamine.
-不用假麻黄素  -不用
- So no Pseudo? - No Pseudo.
你还是有个计划啊
So you do have a plan.
太好了  怀特先生
Yeah, Mr. White!
科学真伟大
Yeah, science!
好了
Okay.
-这是什么  -购物清单
- What's this?  - That is a shopping list.
要搞到其中一些可能有点挑战性
Getting some of those items may be challenging.
"一台自耦变压器  六升的
"One autotransformer, 6 liters an...
水  水合甲  甲胺
Hy... Hydrous Methyl... Methylamine,
两台35m和m的口径管式炉"
Two 35 m&m tube furnaces..."
m和m是指毫米
It's mm, millimeter.
一个70毫米的最好
One 70-millimeter would be fine,
但是它们组合起来很难
But they're hard to combine.
"40克硝酸钍"
"40 grams Thorium Nitrate"?
喂  怀特先生  这些屁东西我读都读不清楚
Yo, Mr. white, I can't even pronounce half this shit.
告诉你  我不玩了
You know what?  Count me out.
我要离开镇子
I'm leaving town.
我要搬去  俄勒冈州之类的
I'm moving to, like, Oregon or something...
杰西  杰西  听我说
Jesse, Jesse, listen to me.
今天只是你未来生活的开始
Today is the first day of the rest of your life.
你这是干嘛
What are you doing?
这是你余生的伊始
This is the first day of the rest of your life,
而你的余生会是怎样的
But what kind of life will it be?
是充满恐惧的余生
Will be be a life of fear,
尽想着"不  不  我做不了"的生活
Of "oh, no, no, no, "I can't do this,"
从不相信自己的生活吗
Of never once believing in yourself?
-我不知道  -听着
- I don't know. - Listen.
这些东西
These things?
我们需要它们
We need them.
只有你能够弄到它们
And only you can get them for us.
准备好了  开始吧
Okay, it's ready. There you go.
宝宝好  我是你玛丽姨妈
Hi, baby. I'm your aunt Marie.
现在  你肯定已经知道我了
Now, of course you already know that because
因为20年后你看这录像时
When you watch this twenty years from now
我还会和现在一模一样
I will look exactly the same as I do now.
我知道这挺不可思议
I know it is amazing.
岁月对我不起作用  不是吗
I have aged shockingly well, haven't I?
总之
Anyway,
欢迎观看你的即将庆生会  梅拉达
Welcome to your baby shower, Esmeralda!
梅拉达
Esmeralda?
Esmeralda.
这就是你名字  你在这里第一次听到
That's your name, and you heard it here first.
那是你帅气的
Now, that is your wonderful,
好哥哥
Handsome older brother.
给她瞧瞧  哥哥的样子
Show her, older brother, your face.
行了  别冲着鼻子
Okay. Not right up the nose.
别  转回来对着我
Not... back to me.
那是你妈妈
There's your mommy!
妈妈好
Hello, mommy!
瞧  这就是你  梅拉达
And look! There you are, Esmeralda!
醒醒吧  宝贝
Wake up, baby!
庆祝时间到
Time to party!
别疯了
Easy.
不管你信不信  梅拉达
Believe it or not, Esmeralda,
庆祝完后  你的名字要改成霍莉
Right after the party, your name was changed to Holly.
而且我相信  汉克  那也是
And I believe, Hank, that was around the time
把你姨妈送进精神病院的时候
That we took aunt Marie to the insane asylum.
对  对  我把她扔在路边
Yeah, yeah. I dropped her off at the curb.
然后我就和仙妮娅·特恩结婚
Then I married Shania Twain
并从此过上幸福的生活
And lived happily ever after.
那是爸爸  说话呀  爸爸
There's daddy! Speak, daddy!
跟你女儿打个招呼
Say hello to your daughter.
霍莉  我非常以你为荣
Holly, I am very proud of you,
我无时无刻不在想着你
And I think about you all the time.
无论你去哪
Wherever you go,
不管你如何生活
Whatever you do in life,
永远记得你身后有一个家庭
Always know that you have a family
每一位家人都爱你至深
Who loves you very, very much.
-干杯  -干杯
- Cheers. - Cheers!
天呐  太漂亮了
Oh, my god, it's so cute.
卡门  这真是  瞧
Oh, Carmen, it's... oh, look.
看看这个  真可爱
Look at that. It's adorable.
我太喜欢了  卡门  谢谢
I love it, Carmen. Thank you.
太客气了  亲爱的
You're so welcome, honey.
谢谢  瞧这小脚丫
Thank you. Look at the little feet.
我送的
From me.
和汉克一起
And Hank.
这包装纸真好看
What nice wrapping paper.
玛丽总能找到最棒的包装纸
Marie always finds the best wrapping paper.
当然
I do.
好了
Okay.
来看看是什么
Let's see what this is.
真令人兴奋
Exciting.
这是
It's a...
头饰
A tiara.
玛丽  这是不是
Marie, is this...
白金嵌着几克拉锆石
White gold and several carats' worth of zircons.
玛丽  你太破费了
Oh, Marie, you spent too much on this.
你不该这样的  真的
You shouldn't have. You really, really shouldn't.
不过这个  真的
But it's so... it's really...
很耀眼
It's... sparkly.
闪闪发光  谢谢你
Sparkly! Like wow! Thank you.
沃尔特  听着
Hey, listen, Walt...
有比啤酒烈的吗
You got anything stronger than beer?
这是太棒了
It's just gor... oh, it's great.
我很喜欢  谢谢你
I love it. Thank you.
谢谢你  亲爱的  谢谢
Thank you, sweetie, thank you.
抱歉  伙计
Sorry, man.
看了200份礼物之后  有点无趣
You know, after 200 presents, it just gets kind of old.
-真是好酒  -可不是吗
- That's nice stuff. - It is, isn't it?
我这正好有配好酒的东西
I got just the thing to go with that.
对不起  我刚没想到
I'm sorry. I wasn't thinking.
不  不  不  没事
No, no, no, no. It's okay.
我能来一支吗
You mind if I have one?
你觉得这样好吗
You think it's a good idea?
汉克  我已经得了肺癌了
Hank, I've already got lung cancer.
好吧  有道理
Okay. You got me there.
谢谢
Thanks.
我帮了个联邦探员的忙
I did a little favor for an FBI guy.
我有种感觉
Now, I was under the impression...
这雪茄不合法  是吧
That these were illegal, hmm?
对  可有时候
Yeah, well, sometimes forbidden fruit
禁果才最甜  不是吗
Tastes the sweetest, doesn't it?
很可笑  不是吗
It's funny, isn't it?
我们怎么划定界限
How we draw that line.
什么
Yeah?
什么界限
What line is that?
就是  什么合法  什么不合法
Well, what's legal, what's illegal,
古巴雪茄  酒
Cuban cigars, alcohol.
你知道  如果是在1930年喝酒
You know, if we were drinking this in 1930,
我们就违法了
We'd be breaking the law.
换个时间  又合法了
Another year, we'd be okay.
谁知道明年又有什么会变合法
Who knows what will be legal next year?
你是说像大麻
You mean like pot?
像大麻  或者
Like pot. Or...
之类的
Whatever.
可卡因  海洛因
Cocaine? Heroin?
我就是随口一说
I'm just saying it's arbitrary.
那你该去监狱看看
Well, you ought to visit lockup.
那里有很多人这么说
You hear a lot of guys talking like that.
伙计  你就为14包大麻抓我啊
"hey, man, why'd you bust me with these 14 bales of ganja?
等明年威利·纳尔逊当总统时
"It's all gonna be legal next year
这可就不犯法了
When Willie Nelson be the president"
老兄  这话也能反过来说
Shit, buddy, it doesn't only go one way, either.
有时候  所谓合法的东西并不该合法化
Sometimes there's stuff that's legal that shouldn't be.
我是指  那混账的冰毒曾经合法
I mean, friggin' meth used to be legal.
曾经在美国的任何一家
Used to sell it over every counter
药房的柜台里都有出售
At every pharmacy across America
感谢上帝  他们知道该禁毒了
Thank god they came to their senses on that one, huh?
对
Yeah.
聚会很棒
Nice party.
一个头冠
A tiara.
给一个新生儿送白金头冠
A white gold tiara for a newborn baby.
是啊
Yeah.
我觉得她是在
You know, I think she got that at
格特鲁德·扎克瑞里买的
Gertrude Zachary produced, yes
我是说  这东西肯定得
I mean, that thing must have cost, like, what,
500还是600吧
$500 or $600.
我觉得我该退掉它
You know what? I think I'm going to return it.
你想好了吗
You sure?
她肯定会发现的
She's bound to find out.
也许我能跟她解释说
Well, maybe I can explain to her that
比起白金的婴儿头饰
We need a diaper than
我们更需要尿布
A white gold baby tiara.
我在想
You know, I've been thinking about
你对戴尔克沃利医生说的话
What you said Dr. Delcavoli
关于辅助的疗法
About alternative medicine.
不  别担心  我再不会提那事了
No. Don't worry. I'm not going to mention that anymore.
不是  我是想说  也许这可行呢
No. What I mean is that maybe there is something to it.
看  这个
Here. look.
在法明顿有这种印第安人的净汗屋
They do this navajo sweat lodge up by farmington.
治疗仪式
Healing ceremony.
据说对肺有好处
It's supposed to be good for your lungs.
不是说我真的信  只是
I'm not saying that I believe in it, but...
你看  或许有有益处
You know, it might be an experience.
你说真的
Really?
你
You?
去汗屋
In a sweat lodge?
我打算周五开车过去  周日回来
I was thinking about driving up on Friday,
如果你同意的话
Coming back Sunday. I mean, if you're okay with it.
我当然同意了
Well, of course I'm okay with that.
-汗屋  -对
- Sweat lodge? - Yeah.
我已经满头大汗了  来搭把手
I'm already sweating. Help me out.
70毫米管式炉  很好
70-millimeter tube furnace. Excellent.
非常好  干得不错
This is excellent. Very good work.
-那就对了  -纯氧
- Damn straight. - Okay. Hydrogen.
电解法制备的  对吧
Electrolytically produced, yes?
对  就你要的那种
Yeah, like you asked. I mean,
这破玩意儿可难找了
This crap wasn't easy to get.
死贵
It was expensive.
甲胺呢  甲胺在哪里
Methylamine. Where's the methylamine?
怎么没看到甲胺
I don't see the methylamine.
那个  有点儿麻烦
Yeah, well, that's where I ran into some trouble.
什么麻烦
What kind of trouble?
这里一半破烂是可以直接买
Well, half this crap I could just buy, right?
但是这个甲胺
But this methylamine...
就不容易搞
Not so easy.
都在仓库里锁着呢
They got it locked down tight.
有几个行家愿意去搞
But I did find some pros who will rip it off for us.
他们开价1万块
But they want 10 grand.
那有什么问题  你钱够的
So what's the problem? You have the money.
原来是够  都差不多花光了
No, had. I already spent almost the whole wad.
我手头剩下两千
I mean, I got, like, 2 grand left.
跟你说了  这些破烂贵着呢
I told you, all this crap was expensive.
那么  那些贼有没有说过
So these thieves, did they say where
他们打算从哪儿偷
They would be stealing it from?
城南一个化学品仓库
Yeah, a chemical supply place south of town.
有警卫  监视录像
They got guards and security cameras,
高门大锁
Big ass steel doors.
所以他们才狮子大开口
That's why these dudes are charging so much.
看什么呢
What?
我们何不自己动手
So why don't we just steal it ourselves?
说真的
Yeah?
我们怎么动手
How are we going to do that?
用这个
With this.
这玩意叫啥来着
So what's this stuff called again?
铝热剂
Thermite.
这东西能破锁吗
And that will cut through a lock?
那锁头可是大家伙
Because this is supposed to be one big ass lock.
二战时期
In World War II,
德国人造了一门超级大炮
The Germans had an artillery piece,
它是世界上最大的炮
It's the biggest in the world.
称作"古斯塔夫巨炮"
Called the Gustav Gun,
有一千吨重
And it weighed a thousand tons.
古斯塔夫巨炮的炮弹重7吨
And the Gustav was capable of firing a 7-ton shell
能精确集中23英里外的目标
And hitting a target accurately 23 miles away.
要是用炸弹去炸
I mean, you could drop bombs on it
连续炸上一个月也无济于事
Every day for a month without ever disabling it.
但如果派突击队
But you drop a commando,
只需一个人
One man,
一袋这个
With just a bag of this...
就能熔化4英寸的钢铁
And he could melt right through 4 inches of solid steel
让那门炮彻底完蛋
And destroy that gun forever.
神哪
Jeez!
所以说
So yes.
什么样的锁都能破
I think it will cut through any lock we're likely to find.
你要把这个退掉
You'd like to return this?
它很漂亮  但我要退
It's very nice, but yes.
它是你们店的  没错吧
Well, it is from the store, isn't it?
没错  真是本店的
Oh, yes. It's from this store.
你有发票吗
Do you happen to have a receipt?
没有  别人送的
No. I don't. It was a gift.
送的
A gift.
威尔逊先生  麻烦过来下
Mr. Wilson, could you step over here, please?
威尔逊先生  请你看住这位女士
Mr. Wilson, I'd like you to watch this lady
我去报警
While I find the police.
你说什么
Excuse me?
女士  这是件被盗的赃物  我相信你也了解
Ma'am, this item is stolen, as I'm sure you know.
请跟我来
Come with me, please.
是的  我要起诉
Oh, yes. I intend to press charges.
好的
Please do.
我们在这等
We'll be here.
听我说  我
Look, I...
我这辈子从没偷过东西
I've never stolen anything in my life, all right?
我说了
I told you.
这头饰是别人送的  新生儿派对礼物
That tiara was a gift. A baby shower gift.
那是谁送的呢
So who gave it to you, then?
我有权不告诉你
I don't think I have to tell you that.
你有权什么都不告诉我
You don't have to tell me anything.
你跟警察讲
You can talk to the police,
而我要告诉他们  我儿媳清楚地记得
And I can tell them how my daughter-in-law remembers
她把头饰拿给一位高个金发女士看
Showing this particular item to a tall blonde woman who,
可是她刚一转身  那女士就拿着它走掉了
When her back was turned, walked right out the door with it.
这就是证据
So there.
是嘛
Oh, yeah?
那我就对3套新闻台说去
Then I can talk to the channel 3 news.
我要告诉他们  你们这些人
Yeah. I can tell them how you people,
在没有一丝一毫证据的情况下
Without a shred, without a modicum of evidence,
非法将一名无辜孕妇拘留
Illegally detained an innocent pregnant woman
在黑暗的储藏室里
In a dank storeroom.
-这是我的办公室  -我认为这是绑架
- This is my office. - I feel I'm being held hostage.
而且  这里空气不够
Furthermore, I'm not getting enough air back here.
我喘不过气
I don't think I can breathe.
哦  上帝呀
Oh, my God.
哦不  我要生了
Oh, no. I'm going into labor.
我要
Yes, I...
你好  我是玛丽  请留言
Hi. You've reached Marie. Do the beep thing.
玛丽  我是斯凯勒  我刚从扎克瑞珠宝店出来
Marie? It's Skyler. I just left Zachary's.
我要马上跟你谈谈
I need to talk to you immediately.
警卫呢  他该过来了
Where's the guard? He's supposed to be coming by.
-他是不是已经过去了  -我不知道
- You think he already passed? - I don't know.
-他来了  -我看见他了
- There he is. - Yeah, I see him.
等他过去
Wait till he passes.
安全了
Okay, it's clear.
-这是什么玩意儿  -店里只有这个
- What the hell is this? - It's all they had.
那就去别的店
Then you go to another store.
-只有这个说明你去错店了  -戴上
- If this is all they had, wrong place. - Just put it on.
你真应该
Of course you can...
成了  我们开始
Okay. This is it.
老天
Oh, God.
-该死  躲起来  -怎么回事
- Dawm. Where... duck. Duck. - What?
他不该回来的  他在做什么
He's not supposed to come back. What's he doing?
老天
Oh, God.
他要去茅厕
He's going to the crapper.
老天
Oh, God.
-背上兜子  -你要干嘛
- Carry your bag. - What? What are you doing?
好了  就是这
Okay, there is it.
声音大不大
Is this going to be loud?
马上就知道了
We'll find out in about ten seconds.
往后站
Stand back.
我的神
Jesus!
怎么回事
What's going on?
-哪有加仑装的  -我不知道
- Where are the gallon jugs? - I don't know.
-天哪  -怎么啦
- God! - What?
我们拿这个走  快点  快
Let's just take this. Come on. Come on.
你开大门干什么
What the hell are you doing opening the door?
不然这东西怎么出去
How are we going to take this thing out?
需要听译
-你开我开有什么区别  -让我试试不行吗
- How is it going to be any different? - Can I just try it?
-行  行  你去吧  -我的神
- Fine, fine, go ahead. - Jesus. Okay.
成了宝贝儿  看看  怎么样
Yeah, baby. See? Eat it, okay?
我无敌了  我无敌了
I'm the king. I'm the king.
不不不  情况不妙
No, no, no. That didn't sound good.
好吧  这事没戏了
Well, this thing's not going anywhere.
事先说下  可不能在我车道上制毒啊
We're not cooking in my damn driveway. I tell you that.
跟你说了慢点  听不懂人话吗
What part of slow it down did you not understand?
你说的太多了  太重了  伙计  你得等我
You talk too much. It's heavy, man. You got to wait for me.
好了
Okay.
就这样  就这样  现在竖起来
That's good, that's good. Now just bring it up.
慢点  慢点  慢点
Easy, easy, easy.
好了
Okay.
你的房产经纪人  啥时候回来
Your real estate agent, when is she supposed to come back?
糟糕
Shit.
我不清楚
Yo, I don't know.
我会确保她不回来
I'll make damn sure she doesn't.
好主意
Good call, yo.
好吧
All right.
将温度保持在425华摄氏度
Keep the temperature steady at 425 degrees.
我们需要制作两个多小时
We'll need to run it two more hours
保证有4.5磅的产量
Try to have enough to make 4.5 Pounds.
4.5  不是4吗
4.5? Not 4?
2磅用来还屠库
2 pounds pays Tuco back.
4.5磅能为我们带来可观的收入
4.5 pounds puts us $44,000 ahead...
每磅44000美元
Each.
太对了  伙计
Right on, man.
对极了
Right on.
再加上昨晚我们弄来的那些甲胺
With the amount of methylamine that we got last night,
不久的将来
We could make 4.5 pounds a week for...
我们每周能制出个4.5磅来
Well, for the foreseeable future.
这要多久
How long is that going to be?
我是说  就你目前的情况而言
I mean in your situation.
你需要多少钱
How much cash do you need?
越多越好
More.
有人在我家院子里
Someone's in my yard.
都在外面  随时随地都有可能进来
Was there, by any chance,
行程安排今天下午参观房屋
Scheduled for this afternoon an open house
我有给他们留言  伙计  不是我的错
I left them a message, man. It's not my fault.
我不管你用什么方法
I don't care how you do it. Just keep
别让他们进来就行  明白了吗
Them out of here. Do you understand?
-明白  -去吧
- Yeah. - Go.
你不可能永远都躲着我
You know you can't duck me forever.
怎么了
What?
别装蒜了  我给你发了15条留言
Come on. I left you, like, 15 messages.
我去办公室找你  你却从后门偷偷溜了
When I went to your office, you snuck out the back way.
我没溜  我只是去吃午饭
I didn't sneak. I was going to lunch.
老天  斯凯勒  你算什么  多疑的警察吗
Jeez, Skyler, what are you, the paranoid police?
玛丽  我长那么大从未如此羞愧过
Marie, I have never been so humiliated in my life.
那个皇冠
That tiara.
他们指控我扎克瑞商店偷的
They accused me at Zachary's of shoplifting it.
你去扎克瑞干嘛
What were you doing at Zachary's?
我想把它退回去
I was returning it.
你退回去了
You were returning it.
为什么要退回去
Why would you return it?
只是
It just wasn't...
玛丽  你怎么了
Marie, what is wrong with you?
能跟我说说吗
Can you please tell me that?
能告诉我你这么做的原因吗
Can you tell me why you'd do such a thing?
这是什么意思  是说你不知道吗
What does that mean? Does that mean you don't know?
这样的意思是
That means that
我根本不知道你在说什么
I have no idea what the hell you're even talking about.
你不知道我在说什么
You have no idea what I'm talking about.
商店  商店行窃
The shop... the shoplifting.
不知道吗
No idea?
你不会承认的  是吧
You're not going to admit this, are you?
我真做不到去承认一件
I can't really admit to something
我一无所知的事
When I have no knowledge of what it is that I'm admitting.
别忘了登记哦
Don't forget to sign in.
-谢谢  -谢谢
- Thank you. - Thank you.
打扰一下  我想看看地下室
Excuse me. I'd just like to see the basement.
-好吧  已经被占用了  -这儿不是洗手间
- Yeah, well, it's occupied. - It's not a bathroom.
我只是想看看地下室  有什么大不了的
I just want to see the basement. What's the big deal?
你别想看地下室了  贱人  明白了吗
Yo, you ain't seeing the basement, bitch. You got that?
房子下沉了  现在给我滚
Is that sinking in? Now beat it.
所有的人都滚蛋  房子不卖了
All of you all. House is not for sale.
滚出这里
Get the hell out!
怎样
So how was it?
算是
Was it a...
一种经历吗
An experience?
当然
Yeah.
绝对算是一种体验吗
It was definitely an experience.
什么味道
What's that smell?
是一种
Yeah. It's...
神圣的纳瓦霍草药
Sacred navajo herbs and...
没事吧
Hey, is everything okay?
不  事实上有事
No. Not really.
事实上  有事
Actually, not at all.
记得玛丽给我们的皇冠吗
You know that tiara that Marie gave us?
记得
Yeah.
她偷来的
Well, she stole it.
是的
Yeah.
我被捕了还把皇冠还了回去
I practically got arrested trying to return it at the store.
天哪
Oh, my god.
她拒绝承认  拒绝道歉
She refuses to admit it. She refuses to apologize.
我都无所适从了
I don't know what to do.
好吧
Oh, well.
人们有时候会为家人做些事
People sometimes do things for their families.
人们有时候会为家人做些事吗
People sometimes do things for their families?
这么说  偷东西还有理了
And, what, that justifies stealing?
算是吧
Yeah.
那儿肯定有些蒸汗室
That must have been some sweat lodge.
你会听信
Are you gonna listening to the
她说的话吗
Words coming out of her mouth?
如果是我你会怎么办
What would you do if it were me?
什么意思
What do you mean if it were you?
如果偷东西的是我  你会怎么办
If it were me, what would you do?
你会跟我离婚吗
Would you divorce me?
还是把我揭发去警局
Would you turn me in to the police?
你不会想知道的
You don't want to find out.
想吃点什么吗
Do you want something to eat?
不用  谢谢
No, thanks.
这玩意是什么  居然是蓝色的
What is this shit? This is blue.
我们用了不同的化学程序
We used a different chemical process,
但从没这么纯过
But it is ever been that's pure
只是颜色蓝色而已  绝对正点
It may be blue, but it's the bomb.
太  太  太正了
Tight! Tight, tight, yeah!
蓝色  黄色  粉色
Blue, yellow, pink.
随便什么颜色  继续供货就行
Whatever, man. Just keep bringing me that.
4.6磅
4.6.
快给钱
Come on.
我说啥来着  这家伙能制毒
And what did I say, man? This guy can cook!
你说得对  说得对
You're all right, man. You're all right.
我们合作能赚好多钱
We're going to make a lot of money together.
记住你的老大是谁
Just remember who you're working for.
你说什么
What did you say?
我只是说说  他们得清楚
I'm just saying they got to know
是为你在卖命
That they're work for you
难道他们不清楚这点吗
Like they don't already know that?
说得好像他们很笨似的
Are you saying that they're stupid?
不  我只是  说说而已
No, I'm just... I'm just saying.
是吗  所以你并没说他们笨
Oh, yeah. So you're not saying that they're stupid.
我不明白了  你是在说我笨吗
So I don't understand. Are you saying that I'm stupid?
没有  别纠结了  屠库  我只是说说
No. Come on, Tuco. I'm just saying.
不对  你抢了我的话
No, you're just speaking for me!
就像我不能说话似的
Like I ain't got the damn sense to speak for myself!
是这样吗  你是这个目的吧
Is that it? Is that what you're doing?
屠库
Tuco.
我们为啥不放轻松点呢
Hey, why don't we all just relax, huh?
海森堡说放轻松
Heisenberg says relax.
口腔  家
Orale, homes.
我放松了
I'm relaxed.
我放松了  我放松了
I'm relaxed. I'm relaxed.
见鬼  看看这个  看看
Damn, man! Look at that! Look!
是啊  不太妙啊
Yeah. That's messed up.
好了  海森堡
Okay, Heisenberg!
下周见
Next week.